devart.com 2019-07-22

# Privacy Policy - Using Devart Website

Devart (“Devart”, “Company”, “us” or “we”), respects and protects privacy of visitors to our website, https://www.devart.com, and the other websites under the devart.com domain (collectively, the “Websites”), and our customers who use our software products and related services (together with the Websites, the “Products”). This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) sets out how we collect, store, process, transfer, share and use data that identifies or is associated with you (“Personal Information”) and information regarding our use of cookies and similar technologies. Before accessing or using our Websites and Products, please ensure that you have read and understood our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this privacy policy. Devart is the data controller of the personal information we hold about you. 

### Personal Information We Collect

#### Essential Account Data

We receive Personal Information directly from you when you provide it to us as part of creating an account on the Websites, including at least: 

  * First Name
  * Email address
  * Password

These data are processed in order to provide you with the Products and secure access to your account. If you choose not to provide Essential Account Data, we may not be able to provide the Products to you or respond to your other requests. 

#### Optional Account Data

As part of creating and maintaining an account with us, you may voluntarily submit additional information, including:

  * Last name
  * Job title
  * Company name

Optional Account Data is used for various purposes: 

  * Last name is collected to improve communication with you.
  * Job title a used by us to understand our user base and for direct marketing purposes.
  * Company name is collected so that you can better and more easily identify yourself to other users on the site.

#### Contact Information

We may collect contact information for both present and prospective customers including name, address, phone number, title and company name, from various sources, including offline marketing activities.

We process this information for marketing purposes and to provide support to present and prospective customers.

#### Billing Information

All primary payment data is collected and retained by our subprocessor for this information, Avangate Inc. (2Checkout). We retain only the record of invoice number, customer name and the billing address, which is stored outside of our Sites and Products. 

Billing information and payment records are processed in order to provide Products to our paid customers and to comply with legal and contractual requirements.

#### Information We Automatically Collect When You Use Our Products

##### Products Usage Data

We collect Products usage data which records certain 'in-product' actions and activities such as 'launching a product', 'open a project', 'format code', etc. We do not scan or collect the content of any file or information that might be displayed by an application or used whilst performing such actions or activities.

##### Device Data

We collect information about your computer, such as operating system, amount of memory, region, language, time zone, browser version, server version.

##### Error reports

If you experience problems with our products we may collect data about the products and any problems you experience with them. This data helps us improve our products and services, to diagnose problems in the products you use, and provide solutions. Depending on your product and settings, error reports can include data such as the type or severity of the problem, details of the software or hardware related to an error, contents of files you were using when an error occurred and the current state of the software. 

##### Preview, Freeware and Free Edition Products

Devart offers preview, freeware and free edition Products or other optional features that will enable you to use them while providing feedback and usage data to Devart.

As a result, these Products may automatically collect additional data, provide fewer controls, and otherwise employ different privacy and security measures than those typically present in our Products. If you participate in previews or pre-release programs, we may contact you about your feedback or your interest in continuing to use the product after general release.

#### Connection Data

If you access our Sites or Products through a third-party connection or log-in or connect an application to the Products or Websites, that third party you connected with may pass certain information about your use of its service to the Products and Websites. This information could include, but is not limited to, the User ID associated with your account, an access token necessary to access that service, any information that you have permitted the third party to share with us, and any information you have made public in connection with that third-party service.

#### Online Form, Email and Chat Data

When you fill out an online form, or engage in email or online chat communications with us, you may voluntarily supply us contact and other information and we may also retain a record of any communications with you or activities you perform. 

Data from these sources is processed in order to supply you with information that you request from us, and may be used for direct marketing and analytic purposes. 

#### Support Ticket Data

When you submit a support ticket through our systems, we will collect company and contact data, and record activity related to your request. 

Information submitted as part of support tickets is processed by us in order to provide help to you in using the Products, to contact you about your request(s), and to improve our products and services. 

#### Blogs and Сommunity Forums

Devart offers publicly-accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information provided in this area may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. If you decide to post something in a public area of our Websites, any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Websites, becomes available to the public, as controlled by any applicable privacy settings. If you remove information that you posted to the Websites, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages of the Websites, or if other Users have copied or saved that information. To request removal of your Personal Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@devart.com.

In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information.

From time to time, we post customer testimonials on the Websites which may contain Personal Information. We obtain the customers’ consent to post their names along with their testimonials.

Information submitted by you to our blogs and community forums is processed by us in order to help users report and resolve problems with the Products, to communicate with users of the Products, and to improve our products and services.

#### Information We Receive From Third Party Sources

Certain Devart services, such as payment processing, information processing or assisting with user evaluation of our products, are offered in conjunction with our (third-party) business partners. In such cases, we may need to share your personal information with them in order to provide these services. In this instance, please note that certain services may be unavailable if you do not want to disclose the personal information you are asked for. Where our services make use of hosted tools, hosted data storage and payment services provided by third parties any of your personal information stored by such third parties shall be subject to their privacy provisions. Whilst we choose our business partners carefully, unfortunately we cannot be responsible for their privacy policies and practices or those of other sites that you access using links from our site. Therefore we recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit. In addition, if you linked to our site from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions. 

### Use and Disclosure of Personal Information

Devart may use Personal Information provided to operate, improve upon, and personalize the Products, for billing identification and authentication, to contact and communicate with you about the Products and your use of the Products, to support use of the Products, to send marketing materials (subject to your opt-out option), for research purposes, and to generally improve the content and functionality of the Products. We may also combine your Personal Information with third-party analytics information to build a broader profile of our individual Users so that we can serve you better and provide custom, personalized content and information. Additionally, we may use the Personal Information we collect for identification and authentication and fraud prevention, to analyze the Websites usage and improve the Products, for internal market research, troubleshooting problems, to enforce our Terms of Service, and as otherwise set forth in this Policy. Note that we will never email you to ask for your account information; if you receive such an email, please forward it to privacy@devart.com. Devart may use your cell phone number to call or text you in order to provide the Products. If you would like more information about our policy, or to opt out, please review our Terms of Service. We use financial information solely as authorized by you in accordance with the Products, in order to process your payments. 

#### Third-Party Processors

Devart shares Personal Information with its third party service providers (such as its credit card processors and hosting partners) to provide the necessary hardware, software, networking, storage, and other services we use to operate the Products and maintain a high quality user experience. We use third party analytics tools to help us measure traffic and usage trends for the Products and Websites. These tools collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including the web pages you visit, your browser add-ons, and other information that assists us in improving the Products. Devart may store Personal Information in third-party marketing, CRM and mail-management software, in order to facilitate interactions with users or potential customers. In all situations where Devart discloses Personal Information to third parties acting as service providers or "agents" on behalf of Devart, Devart will require the recipient to protect and only use Personal Information in accordance with this Policy. We do not permit our service providers to use the Personal Information we share for their marketing purposes. 

#### Analytics and Logs

We may collect and use the analytic information from our own systems and from third parties together with your Personal Information to build a broader profile of our individual Users so that we can serve you better. Devart gathers certain information automatically and stores it in log files. This information includes internet protocol addresses as well as browser, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, search terms, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. Occasionally, we may collect Personal Information to information gathered in our log files, as necessary to improve the Products for individual customers. Otherwise, we generally use this information as we would any Usage Data, to analyze trends, administer and maintain the Products and the Websites, or track usage of various features within the Products. 

#### Other Information Sharing

In addition to the purposes described above, we disclose Personal Information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, on legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also share such information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations or our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. We may share information, including Personal Information with any member of Devart which includes any entity that controls, is controlled by, or under common control with Devart. 

### Storing and Transferring Your Personal Information

We implement appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal information against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, change or damage. All personal information we collect will be stored on our secure servers. All electronic transactions entered into via our Websites will be protected by SSL encryption technology. We will never send you unsolicited emails or contact you by phone requesting your account ID, password, credit or debit card information or national identification numbers. 

### Your Rights in Respect of Your Personal Information

You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Information, including those set forth below. For more information about these rights, or to submit a request, please email [privacy@devart.com](mailto:privacy@devart.com). Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your request, such as if it is frivolous or extremely impractical, if it jeopardizes the rights of others, or if it is not required by law, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision. In some cases, we may also need to you to provide us with additional information, which may include Personal Information, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request.

#### Access

You can request more information about the Personal Information we hold about you and request a copy of such Personal Information. You can also access certain of your Personal Information by accessing your account settings or contacting us at [privacy@devart.com](mailto:privacy@devart.com).

#### Rectification

If you believe that any Personal Information we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You can also correct some of this information directly by accessing your account settings or contacting us at [privacy@devart.com](mailto:privacy@devart.com).

#### Erasure

You can request that we erase some or all of your Personal Information from our systems.

#### Withdrawal of Consent

If we are processing your Personal Information based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Information, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Services.

#### Portability

You can ask for a copy of your Personal Information in a machine-readable format.

#### Objection

You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your Personal Information for certain purposes.

#### Restriction of Processing

You can ask us to restrict further processing of your Personal Information.

#### Right to File Complaint

You have the right to lodge a complaint about Company’s practices with respect to your Personal Information with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State.

### Cookies and Similar Technologies

### What are Cookies

Our Sites use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Sites. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Sites and also allows us to improve our Sites.

Cookies are pieces of code that allow for personalisation of our Sites experience by saving your information such as user ID and other preferences. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes.

#### Cookies we Use

We use the following types of cookies:

### First-Party Cookies

We utilize session cookies, which allow us to uniquely identify your browser while you are logged in and to process your online transactions. Session cookies disappear from your computer when the web browser is closed or computer is turned off. Session cookies are required for site operation. We also utilize persistent cookies to make it easier to log into and use the Products. Persistent cookies remain on computers after the web browser is closed or the computer is turned off. 

### Third Party Cookies

These cookies provide information that is used to the help us understand how our Sites are being used, to measure the effectiveness of marketing campaigns, and to help customize the Websites for you.

Information gathered from third-party cookies and from your browser can include:

  * IP address
  * Device identifiers (see below for more information)
  * Web browser information
  * Hardware and software information
  * Page view statistics
  * Browsing history
  * Usage information
  * Location information
  * Time of access

#### Managing Cookies

The cookies we use are designed to help you get the most from the Websites but if you do not wish to receive cookies, most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of our Sites. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. If you only want to limit third party advertising cookies, you can turn such cookies off by visiting the following links (please bear in mind that there are many more companies listed on these websites than those that drop cookies via our Sites): 

  * Your Online Choices [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/)
  * Digital Advertising Alliance <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>

If you have any questions about our use of cookies or other technologies, please email us at [privacy@devart.com](mailto:privacy@devart.com).

### Links to Third Party Websites

the Products and the Websites contain links to websites and applications other than the Websites and the Products, including websites and applications operated by affiliates and other third parties. Please be aware that we do not determine and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of websites and applications operated by third parties. Your browsing and interaction on any third party website or service, including those that have links on our Sites, are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the Products or the Websites, and read the privacy statements of third party websites and applications linked to the Products. Devart does not endorse and is not responsible for the practices of third parties or their websites or applications. In addition, you agree that we are not responsible for and we do not control any third parties that you authorize to access your User Content. If you are using a third party website or service and you allow such a third party access to your User Content, you do so at your own risk. This Policy applies only to information collected by the Products and the Websites. 

### Data Retention

Devart will retain Personal Information we process on behalf of our customers or collect directly from our customers for as long as needed to provide Service to our customers, subject to our compliance with this Policy. We may further retain and use this Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, maintain accurate accounting, financial and other operational records, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We have established internal policies for the deletion of data from customer accounts following termination of a customer’s subscription to the Products. 

### Our Policy Towards Children

Devart does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Information through our Websites. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Information on our Websites without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Information to Devart through our Websites, please contact us, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information from our databases. 

### Changes to This Policy

We may update this Policy from time to time and so you should review this page periodically. When we change this privacy policy in a material way, we will update the “last modified” date at the end of this privacy policy. Changes to this Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.
